♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 11=
We're home.
How about I walk you to your room?
You're a lady. I should walk you back.
You've held the umbrella all day.
You must be tired.
Let me walk you back.
Holding an umbrella isn't tiring.
Where's the umbrella?
It doesn't matter.
How about
we part here and go back?
Okay.
Are you hungry?
No.
But I'm a bit thirsty.
Aunt's pastry was too salty.
Sorry.
How about I get you...
Xu Xian, what's wrong?
I'm fine. You may go back.
Xu Xian! Xu...
Xu Xian, what's wrong with you?
Xu Xian!
What's wrong with you, Xu Xian?
- Xu Xian!
- I'm fine.
Open the door!
Just go back.
Xu Xian!
Xu Xian, open the door! Xu Xian!
Xu Xian, what's wrong?
(Backlash?)
(How does he have
the Du'e Ancient Scroll?)
(How can a mortal withstand this?)
The Du'e Ancient Scroll
is an ancient artifact.
I can only help you
suppress the backlash temporarily.
Xu Xian.
How do you feel?
Just now, dark smoke came out
of the scroll and burrowed into you.
Is it some kind of evil object?
No.
It's the Du'e Ancient Scroll.
Master Hanshan passed it on to me.
What is the Du'e Ancient Scroll?
The Du'e Ancient Scroll
is an ancient artifact.
It possesses the purest energies,
and can redeem demons.
Redeem demons?
Using your body?
I just suffer some backlash.
You hate demons the most.
Why would you help them?
Not really.
I only hate the demon
who killed my parents.
Master told me
all beings struggle
on their cultivation,
and they all deserve a second chance.
Some demons are not evil by nature,
and haven't committed terrible crimes.
They've simply lost their way.
If someone guides them properly,
they can turn from evil to good,
and get on the right path.
Then what about the demon
who killed your parents?
Would you give him a second chance too?
I don't know.
But I would definitely ask him
why he killed my parents.
Why?
- Amitabha.
- Why?
- Poor grass.
What did the grass ever do to you?
Cut the nonsense!
Why are you so angry?
You humans are so annoying.
Your lifespans are as short as insects,
yet your desires are endless.
You are also being consumed
by your own desires right now.
Mind your own business.
See? You're ashamed into anger.
Can't steady your sword.
So I get it right.
Think I can't deal with you?
The Leifeng Pagoda contract
still stands.
Whenever I want,
I can even make you kill yourself.
Pretty.
Are you really going to watch me die?
I'm not letting you die.
Thank you.
That scared me.
What's so bad about being a demon?
We live longer than humans.
We can travel around
and do whatever we want.
Why must we become an immortal?
Look at those immortals in heaven,
they're all so fake and insincere.
So boring.
Love?
Xu Xian's lifespan is shorter than
the time it takes to sober up from a drink.
Yet Suzhen pours her true feelings
into this fleeting romance.
Fool.
This is fate.
All beings have their own fate.
Bai Suzhen has hers.
Xu Xian has his.
So do I.
So do you.
Fahai, let me ask you,
if love is so wonderful,
why is it a trial?
I don't understand.
Love is born from desire.
Desire arises from craving,
and the trial begins.
Then I'll crave too.
I want to be with Suzhen forever.
Is this my trial?
Look at this half-snake,
half-drake freak.
An unnatural monster.
Strip it bare
to check its gender.
You lesser demons!
How dare you pick on the weak
in here?
Do you want to revert
to your original forms?
Miss Bai, sorry.
We won't dare to do it again.
Get lost now!
So you're that mixed-blood demon?
I've never seen
a little snake with horns before.
So adorable.
You're so beautiful.
Don't you think I'm weird and ugly?
How could you be ugly?
You're the most adorable snake
I've ever seen.
I'll take you as my younger sister.
What do you think?
I'm used to being alone,
but you're cute enough
for me to make an exception.
From now on, you'll be
the only important person by my side.
Alright?
You said I'm the only one.
I know you won't
get over this right away.
Why don't you just wait and see?
See if Bai Suzhen abandons you
when Xu Xian's with her.
Be quiet?
Then it's settled.
Change back into men's clothes.
Let's go to Cuiyu Pavilion
and have a drink.
I promise you,
we won't go home until we're drunk.
No. You'll go drink by yourself.
Wait for me.
- Come on.
Cheers.
How did I lose again?
Did you secretly use spells?
If you can't afford to lose, don't play.
Seriously.
The contract with you
is affecting my luck.
Pretty,
how about you
just release me from it first?
After you do, we can play another round,
and I definitely won't lose.
Forget about your little schemes.
I'm not drunk.
Another round.
Come on, cheers.
Cheers.
Qing?
How did you get so drunk?
You're Miss Bai's bodyguard.
If she's in danger,
how will you protect her?
Bodyguard?
You are here.
You're drunk. I'll take you home.
I'm not drunk.
My mind is clear, perfectly clear.
Suzhen likes you so much,
As a grown man,
why are you being so hesitant?
I've been through thick and thin
with Suzhen for so many years.
Who do you think you are?
I understand her better.
I care about her more.
But now, because of you,
she's about to abandon me.
Qing, you really are drunk.
I'm not drunk.
Listen carefully.
You must treat Suzhen well.
If you dare to betray her,
I won't let you off.
I will definitely
rip your tendons out,
skin you, and cut you to pieces.
Qing.
You...
- Qing.
- Suzhen.
What's wrong, Qing?
Suzhen.
Do you like Xu Xian,
and not like me anymore?
Young Master Xu.
You two should go.
Xu Xian, just let me explain.
Qing, you've messed things up.
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪